Sun fit and well advantage or poo pasual
plan. Is it a good plan and my lifetime
income and is this plan for you? Let's
talk about it. Hi guys, my name is Ador
Flores. I make videos about money. And
today we're going to be talking about
the Sun Fitin well advantage plan from
Sunlife. Disclaimer, I have been a
Sunlife financial advisor for 2 years
now and I have a lot of clients who has
this plan nationwide. By the way, we are
not going to use any jargon. So, we're
just going to use simple words so we can
all easily understand. Back then, we
used to call it a Polo Pascal plant.
This is what it looks like. I think
you've seen it before. But now, 2026,
it's now changed into an Asian woman. So
this is what it looks like. It's no
longer Purop Pasqual, but it still has
the same benefits. So maybe Purop Pascal
and Sunlife has ended their contract. I
don't know about that. We'll clarify
that later. So anyways, let's talk about
what it's all about. Sunfit and Well is
a life insurance plan with health
insurance and savings. Savings, huh, not
investment. So meaning this is not a VUL
insurance plan. That is for a different
video. First things first, let's talk
about the difference between life
insurance and health insurance. Life
insurance is the money we are going to
leave to our loved ones or beneficiary.
That happens when we pass away. For
example, our son fit and well has a life
insurance of 1 million pesos. So if we
die, our loved ones get 1 million pesos
taxfree. So, what happens to the 1
million pesos? Basically, nothing is
dictated to what you should do with the
1 million pesos. You could use it to pay
for the funeral expenses. Your family
could use it for to continue their
education, pay estate taxes, and if
there are more money or my SORA s 1
million for example, you have used up
400,000 pesos and then my extra 600,000
pesos. that 600,000 pesos belongs to you
or your family. So meaning you do not
return the extra money to sunlife. That
is for your family. Now talaga for
health insurance nan that is the time
that we get money when we get critically
sick. So there is a specific list of
this. I will show you later what it is.
If we get hit by one of those that is
the time we get 1 million pesos taxfree
and we are still alive. So for example
heart attack and then my hospital bill
is 300,000 pesos. Even if my hospital
bill is only 300,000 pesos, Sunlife will
still give me the 1 million pesos and
then the extra money after everything
that is deducted. No, you pay 300,000
pesos to the hospital. So you have
700,000 pesos left. The 700,000 pesos is
still yours. You do not return it to
Sunlife. So that's the reason why if you
know friends of friends or people you
may know or people you see online that
one of their families died or one of
their family members got critically sick
suddenly my parent
because of their insurance plans. It's
very important that we have both life
and health insurance because no matter
how much we gym, we run, we pickle ball
or ano anoa. We can never guarantee just
because we are physically fit and we eat
healthy
critically sick. No, the world does not
work that way. So, it's still possible
that we can still get critically sick
even if we do all of those. No, I run, I
gym, I pickle ball, I skate, I do all of
those. I'm still very health consscious
now. one day if that happens
simply because
speaking of critical illnesses, the
Sunfitit and Well plan covers 114
critical illnesses both major and minor
which is very very comprehensive because
compared to other plans other budget
plans only cover 36 critical illnesses.
So huge difference right there. So when
you look at the 114 critical illnesses
right here menu
actually so it is designed that way
future
just in case we get critically sick. So
it's designed that way. Who doesn't want
more peace of mind or more protection
that this plan offers? So just to recap
again, life insurance is money we leave
to our loved ones when we pass away and
health insurance is money we get when we
get critically sick. It is also very
worth mentioning that the sun fit and
well advantage plan covers you until age
100. So most of the plans, the basic or
the cheap ones only insure you until age
70. Meaning if you if something happens
to you at age 71 paas then you will
basically get nothing because your plan
has already expired at age 70. So yeah
that's basically a good thing to
highlight as well about this plan. Now
let's talk about the qualifications to
claim for life insurance claims. If we
get approved today and we die tomorrow
that is still claimable. So even if you
have only deposited once, we are still
eligible to claim the life insurance
money for example 1 million pesos. This
means that once you are approved, the
life insurance part benefit is already
effective right away. Now the next
question here is what does this cover?
So it covers natural death, accidental
death, let's say sickness death. The one
thing that it does not cover is su. When
it comes to health insurance claim, the
client must not be diagnosed with any
critical illness for 90 days. That is 3
months. This is to check if the client
is being honest. So in the first 90
days,
we will get refunded depending on what
happened to you. after 90 days
but of course medical documents will be
required. So we will check your doctor's
papers, hospital records for us to give
you the claim. So just look at all of
these claims from you see from Facebook.
It's very easy. You can do it through
online banking. You can get it through
check or you can even get it through
code cash. For minor critical illness
claims, it works in percentages. So it
is 20% for the first claim, 20% for the
second claim, and for the third claim,
it is 10%. So let's say you have 1
million pesos of health insurance, that
is a total of 500,000 pesos. So 20%,
200k, 20%, another 200k, and then 10%
100,000 pesos. the rest of the 500,000
pesos will be reserved for your life
insurance or your major critical
illness. Now, when it comes to major
critical illness, let's say you get hit
by a major right away, like for example,
stroke, a heart attack, or cancer, then
you will get the 1 million pesos right
away, 100%. So, it's no longer chop chop
chop. So, again, claims can be received
through check, cash, or bank transfer.
and I will be the one to personally
deliver it to you if I am your personal
financial advisor. So just message me if
you haven't gotten an advisor already.
All right. So now let's talk about
paying period. So if you are not aware,
insurance plans out there that require
you to pay all throughout your life and
there are insurance plans out there that
only has a limited paying period. For
example, 5 years to pay, 10 years to
pay, 15 years to pay, or 20 years to
pay. The good thing here is that even if
you only pay for 10 years, 15 years, or
whichever you prefer, you are insured
until age 100. The longer the paying
period, the cheaper it is. The shorter
the paying period, the higher the
premium also, but faster.
So, whichever you prefer. Common
question that we have to insert here.
What happens if fully paid something
happened to me and fully paid? Let's say
I got critically sick or I died. Let's
say you have a 20 years sunfit and well
plan. You paid for 3 years. So you have
17 years left. Will we still be able to
claim the 1 million pesos even if you
fully paid? The answer is yes. And now
continue payments by your family. So
once you get the money, health insurance
or life insurance money, the contract is
automatically ended. 1 million pesos
claim is 1 million pesos claim tax-free
and of contract. Now let's talk about
the other benefits because sun fit and
well is not just about life insurance
and health insurance. So it has other
benefits as well. Third benefit is it
has an additional 50% or for example
500,000 pesos additional if you get hit
by a specific cancer. So this is the
list of specific cancers. If we get hit
by one of these there's an additional
50% or 500,000 pesos. So for males we
have here prostate testicular and then
we have for females we have here breast
cervix cancer. very common for both
males and females. So if you get hit by
one of these, that's 1 million pesos
health insurance plus 500,000 pesos for
specific cancer benefit. Fourth benefit
we have here is daily hospitalization.
So every day we are in the hospital, we
get income. Fifth benefit, once we are
out of the hospital, we get 5,000 pesos
or we receive money once we get out of
the hospital. Sixth benefit is when we
are at home recovering, we are still
receiving money. So while we are in the
hospital, we get out of the hospital and
we are home recovering. Each and every
single one of those, we get money. We
are paid every single day. The
qualifications to get these claims is
that it must be because of one of the
114 critical illnesses. So random now
you go there because you have a fever or
you have a low bowel movement. No, it's
not like that. Okay. So it must be under
one of these. So benefit is called
palative care benefit. Basically life
provides a certain amount for example
six digits for you to enjoy your money
because we got hit by a terminal
illness. So on top of the health
insurance benefit, on top of the
additional 50%, you also have this
benefit. So it's very very
comprehensive. So in total there is a
total of nine insurance benefits in the
POLO Pascal plan or the Sanitinal plan.
Now let's talk about the savings part of
the POP Pascal plan. So basically there
are three sources of income you can get
from the Popo Pascal plan. Let's talk
about each and every single one of them.
First type of saving, it's like an
advanced payout. So from your 1 million
pesos face amount or from your 1 pesos
insurance, it pays you 50,000 pesos per
year from age 65 to 72. So parang
retirement or advanced payout, whatever
you may call it. Second type of income
is called dividends. So let's just call
it reward money so that we can
understand it simply. So every single
year we will receive dividends. It's not
a guaranteed amount. It can go up, it
can go down. After we are fully paid, we
are going to receive dividends every
single year until age 100. So that's the
lifetime income part of this Pure
Pasqual plan. And then the third income
you can get from this plan is a cash
back. So it's a cashback reward. It's
worth six digits. So you have here your
first income, your second income, and
third income. All of those, by the way,
you will start receiving once you are
fully paid. And every single one of
those is tax-free. So, you can withdraw
all of those or you also have the option
to leave it with Sunlife to accumulate.
So, what does that mean? So, let's say
you have 50,000 pesos payout and then
next year you also have 50,000 pesos
payout, but you did not withdraw it. So
instead of getting 100,000 pesos because
of the 4% that you left it with Sunlife,
it grows 4% every year and it compounds.
So instead of 100,000 pesos, you get
let's say 104,000
pesos. So it increase everything here,
the dividends, the cash back, other
source of income, all of those will grow
4% if you leave it with Sunlife. But if
you want to withdraw it, there's no
problem there as well. But if you want
like long-term growth, especially if you
are young, like you're in your 20s, 30s,
it's really best to leave it with
sunlight to accumulate and then just
withdraw it when you retire or something
like that. And there's more. So
gradaming benefits and then income and
then meron extra perks. So if you have a
sun fit and well plan or the poo paspal
plan, you have this special website
called go well where you can avail
discounts to specific restaurants,
specific gyms and other establishments.
So perks now let's answer a common
question. What if
insurance then good, right? That's very
good news. Very very good news. Now
again there are three types of income
you can get from the POP Pascal plan.
Guaranteed cash benefit from 65 years
old to 72 years old. Number two is
yearly dividends until age 100. And
number three is cash back once you are
fully paid. All of which if you decide
to leave with Sunlife they will have a
chance to grow 4% which is significantly
higher compared to what banks give you.
All right. So, let's look at a sample
here. 30 years old male, 10 years to
pay. So, let's look at him at age 65.
So, at age 65, he'll be able to withdraw
44,000 pesos from income number one. And
then he'll be able to withdraw 472,000
pesos from income number two. And then
he'll be able to withdraw 138,000 pesos
from income number three. So, that's
around what? 600 to 700,000 pesos
withdrawal and he only paid 50,000 pesos
per year for 10 years. So a total of
500,000 pesos
profit and then insured pa until age
100. And even if you withdraw
specifically for income number two, the
dividends part, even if you withdraw all
of those, you will still receive
dividends for next year and the next
next year until age 100.
In short, in short,
now let's talk about my final thoughts.
In conclusion, is this a good plan for
you? The answer is yes. Of course, it's
a good plan if you don't have any health
insurance coverage whatsoever.
Additional tip l do not get an insurance
plan that is money focused cuz as you've
noticed Pascal plan or sunfit and well
is more on health insurance or health
focus, no insurance focus. There are
insurance plans cuz now money focused.
If you get a plan like that and then you
don't have any health insurance
whatsoever,
no one or Sunlife cannot help you. The
company cannot help you because you did
not get yourself a health insurance
plan. So first things first, insurance
plan and then you can get the money
making plan later. Imagine no you get
critically sick and then Sunlife cannot
help you because your plan does not have
any health insurance. So that's a very
wrong move. So basically life and health
insurance plan ma before you moneym
plans or investment plans later nan if
you want to get this plan just message
me on Facebook this is my link it's in
my bio if you want me to be your
personal financial advisor just message
me and of course if you have any
thoughts or questions leave them in the
comment section. Don't forget to like,
comment and share this video. Thank you
for watching and remember to make every
pesa count.